

# Devendra Talvadekar

Senior Construction Manager

### **CAREER SUMMARY**

Entirely constructed 8.6 Million sqft of infrastructure relating to Mixed Used Development, Health care, Residential & Commercial and estate industry. With absolute planning, execution and management, including resolution of on the-spot arising situations provided ultimate coordination from stakeholders to government authorities to workers. With the use of undeniable communication and collaboration provided successful design solutions with constant progressive assessment. Monitoring accompanied with guidance for all the levels, as a part of broad in depth subject knowledge could work upon all including pricing, purchase, methodology, quality check etc. Whole and sole working hand and head for converting ideas into reality with creativity. Undivided extensive 23 Years of work Experience as a seasoned engineering Senior Project & Construction manager.

### **CONTACT**



+919892507653



https://www.linkedin.com/in/devendra-talvadekar-9b2aa436/



tanvi180206@gmail.com



BORIVALI (WEST), MUMBAI-400092, MAHARASHTRA.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Senior Construction Manager

Reliance Industries Ltd, Mumbai | Jul 2017- Present

Project: Jio World Centre, BKC, Bandra

It is Mixed Used Development consist of Convention & Exhibition centre, 2000seater performing Art Theatre, Retail and Office units, Restaurant with Hospitality centre Including extraordinary facilities of 6000+ car parking spaces.

- Functionally Build an all usage development project Including extraordinary facilities of 6000+ car parking spaces, Retail and Office units, Hospitality centre.
- Harmoniously Initiated and eventually developed cordial relationships with clients.
- Scheduled the project in logical steps to meet the requirements of time and budget.
- Reviewed drawings, specifications, materials, estimates, change orders, finances with attention to details.
- Prepared contracts and negotiated revisions, changes and additions to related agreements with architects, consultants, clients, suppliers and subcontractors.
- Effortlessly formulated concepts, strategies, process, quality control.
- Analyzing and managing sites of multidisciplinary projects with quantity, quality and judicious usage of material hence executing them within time and cost boundary.
- Seamlessly integrated technical aspects with core design team and support staff by timely training as well as proactive monitoring with the usage of interpersonal skills.
- Evaluate construction methods & determine the cost-effectiveness of plans.

## Senior Construction Manager

Reliance Corporate IT Park Ltd, Mumbai | Aug 2013 - Jun 2017 Project Details:-Jio world Garden, BKC, Bandra

- Efficiently handled the making of the Jio garden, which had a Multi-level car parking system enough to encompass 2000 cars at a time with Event Field Turf surrounding by landscape & water features.
- Timely prepared and submitted budget estimates and progress as well as cost tracking reports.
- Reengineered and carried out Refurbishment and Fit-out at Dhirubhai Ambani International School, BKC, Mumbai.

#### **EDUCATION**

Completed B.E.Civil in 1998 with 61%

### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

- Expert in MEP coordination.
- Specialist for costing, quantity, and quality estimation and assurance.
- Executed interior fit-outs and project management as a resourceful person.
- Proficient in managing team and work.
- Possessing vendor management competency.
- All-rounder planning with precise drawing checking to on-site execution.
- Acquired exceptional communication skills for smooth functioning.

### **SKILLS**

- 1. Team Management
- 2. Delegation.
- 3. Leadership.
- 4. Organization.
- 5. Communication.
- 6. Prioritizing.
- 7. Planning.
- 8. Risk Management.
- 9. Goal Setting.
- 10. Open to Feedback

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Windows
- Ms Office
- AutoCAD
- MS Project

## Senior Construction Manager

Cushman & Wakefield | TCS IT Park - Mumbai Nov 2012 - Apr 2013

- Precisely coordinated civil and interior works by being in constant interaction with architects during the execution.
- · Handing Over IT Bldg to Client for usage

## **Project Manager**

Supra Estate (I) Pvt. Ltd, Mumbai | Jun 2010 - Oct 2012 A) Project Details:-Construction of 500 Bed Healthcare Building, Andheri.

- Actively Constructed 9 storey, Double basement 500 Bed Healthcare Building within stipulated time and finance.
- Clearly communicated with contractors for skilled workmanship and supervised the same.
- Versatilely handled site working and material input with quality control and quantity check.

## B) Construction of Multi-level Sport, Leisure & Retail Complex with Hospitality Centre.

 Prepensely designed plans and solutions for multilevel sports, leisure, and retail complex with double basements and 9 floors at maximum as a Hospitality center.

## Civil Manager

Unitech Ltd. | March 2008 - May 2010

- Major part of constructing multiusage G+7,13,22 storey buildings, Residential complex, Shopping malls with selfless contribution.
- Successfully executed civil and interior work along with reviewing bills and communicating with architects.

## Senior Engineer Project Coordinator

Unity Infra Projects Ltd, Mumbai | Oct 2005 - Feb 2008

- Developed TATA Clinic and Faculty block of G+13 storey Hospital Building.
- Systematically managed the sites with labour and materials of required quantity as well as quality and achieved the best price by tactical negotiation with contractors
- Effective coordination with civil and interior works of the hospital to connect it with the administration building.

### **AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Efficiently constructed Jio world Garden with 7 millions Safe man hours.
- Flourishingly completed building Jio World Center with 70 millions + Safe Man Hours.
- Operations of construction projects under me like Jio World Garden and TCS projects are fully functioning now hasslefree.

### **HOBBIES**

- Mentoring and Coaching
- Habitat for Humanity Volunteer
- Reading
- Exercising
- Travelling
- Music

## Senior Engineer

Reliance Engineering Associate Pvt Ltd, Gujarat. Oct 2004 - Sep 2005

### **Handled Construction of Jamnagar Refinery**

- Intensive work for Technical coordination with Mechanical, Piping, Electrical and HSE Departments.
- Key Outputs in construction of; Sub Stations, Pipe Racks, Footing for Liquid Ammonia Plant as well as Desalination, Cooling Towers etcetera for various CPP, PRU, SULPHUR, COKER, RTF units.

### **Project Senior Engineer**

Kushal Engineering Associate Pvt Ltd Gujarat Feb 2001 - Sep 2004

## Handled telecommunication Project for Reliance Infomm, Mumbai.

- Structurally completed trenching, ducting, OFC pulling with Man-holes, Installation Roof Top BTS, Construction of Pile & Raft foundation for 32mtr Structural steel towers.
- Leaded & Supervised contractors Team to achieve completion targets.

### **Junior Engineer**

Satyam Realtors Pvt Ltd. (HDIL Company) 1999 - 2001

Purposely Constructed Residential towers of G+7,14 storey buildings on time.

## References

References Available Upon Request.